Gemini Jain

(206) 839-7974 Bothell, WA, 98012

geminijain05@gmail.com
https://github.com/geminijain/

Summary

- 3+ years of Software Development Engineer in Test experience in banking domain, and e-commerce industry.
- Strong knowledge of data structures, automation and algorithms.

Technical Skills

Technology	ASP.Net, MVC
Automation testing tools	Selenium WebDriver/IDE/GRID, QTP, Junit/TestNG, NUnit, Coded UI, Postman,
	Jenkins
Defect tracking tools	Quality Center, VSTS
Language	Java, C#
Methodology	Agile
Defect reporting tools	BugZilla, Firebug, TestRail and Jira
Database	SQL Server 2016

Professional Experience

People Tech Group, Bellevue, WA

Jan, 2018 –

Present

Software Development Engineer in Test

Working on test automation framework for web application using Selenium with C#, and WPF application using CodedUI with C#. Review, write and maintain manual test cases as per user requirement.

Responsibilities:

- Review business requirement documents, user requirement specification and create test strategy and test plan.
- Understand requirement and write automation for manual test cases.
- Create POC for automation framework in Selenium using C#
- Working on test automation framework from started from scratch in Selenium
- Create and run collection of test scripts for API testing using postman tool.
- Create and execute web performance test using VSTS in performance environment
- Create CodedUI test automation framework for WPF application
- Work on user stories assigned for testing in VSTS and perform follow-ups on it.
- Manually test the application and log bugs in VSTS.

InConsulting

Jun, 2017 - Dec, 2017

Junior Software Developer

Build e-commerce website using ASP.Net, C# MVC framework, worked with RESTful API, stored procedures. Participated from scratch with requirement gathering, class diagram, data base design for payment module and integrated the payment section for the website.

Responsibilities:

- Requirement gathered from client, prepared class diagram database diagram
- Integrated PayPal api for e-commerce website.
- Create and run test case for RESTful API using postman and verify the quality of product.

uTest

Jan, 2017 – Jun, 2017 Freelancer, Role: tester

Responsibilities:

- Reviewed business requirement documents and user requirement specification.
- Revised the test plan for maximum functionality coverage.
- Worked on various test cycle, performed mobile testing on android, iOS devices, web application testing on different browsers, reported bugs and reviewed fix successfully.

Software Testing Help

Oct, 2016-Jan, 2017

Project: http://www.carguruji.com/shop/

Description: osCommerce online merchant is a free online shop e-commerce solution under continuous development by the open source community. Its core features allows store owners to setup, run, and maintain their online stores with absolutely no software costs or license fees involved, and with no programming or technical knowledge needed.

Responsibilities:

- Developed automation test scripts using selenium IDE and selenium web driver.
- Identification of GUI elements using various selenium Locators like ID, Name, Link Text, Partial Link Text, XPath, CSS, and DOM in creating automation scripts.
- Worked on hybrid framework for selenium.
- Implemented Page Object Model for various scenarios.

Pactera Technologies, Redmond, WA, USA

Feb, 2015 - July, 2015

Speech Recognition Tester

- Tested speech recognition software for accuracy.
- Handled unique data analysis requests from a range of data customers
- Listened to scripts, report tags to script with responsive results for Cortana, to improve its quality.

Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd., Client: Discover Bank, USA

April, 2013 – July, 2014

Software Engineer

Project Release 12.1: Expansion of discover credit card for Canadian merchandise

Description: Verification of interchange fee for issuer and merchant bank for Canadian currency including various factors like merchant code, transaction type, conversion rate etc. Gained business knowledge of network and peripheral systems, merchant boarding, authorization, clearing, settlement, pricing & disputes.

Responsibilities:

- User Acceptance Testing (UAT) for different business areas involved in network.
- Created test cases, as well as covering all test conditions and eliminating redundancy and duplication
- Defects logging and focused on defining best practices and meeting quality standards and delivery deadlines.

Project Release 12.2: Enhancement in dispute process for Canada merchants

Description: Verification of dispute process for merchant and to improve Discover Network Dispute System **Responsibilities:**

- Performed user acceptance testing of Discover Network Dispute System (DNDS) for raising disputes.
- Performed web based application testing of Discover network dispute system.
- Executed SQL queries to validate dispute raised at backend.
- Delivered proof of concept as compatibility of website with Selenium IDE.

Community Activities

- High School workshop manager at ChickTech Seattle, actively leading Software & Robotics workshops for young girls to empower women in Tech.
- Volunteered as Computer Instruction Assistant at The Seattle Public Library.
- Member of WeKare a Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR) initiative for the associates of Capgemini, India.

Certifications

- International Software Testing Quality Board (ISTQB)
- Quality Center(QC)

Education

• Bachelors Of Engineering in Electronics and Communication Engineering, 2012 Rajeev Gandhi Technical University, Bhopal, MP, India.